# Mateusz Kluczek

### Personal details

I am self-motivated, committed and determined in achieving my goals. I have a clear, logical mind with a practical approach to problem solving. I also have a firm sense of responsibility and capacity to work under pressure with experience in working for international financial institutions.

Nationality: Polish

e-mail: kluczek.m@gmail.com

mobile: +353834874877

www: mateusz-kluczek.github.io

## Education

October 2015 - now Funded PhD in Applied Mathematics, University College Cork

Cork, Ireland

Supervisor: Dr David Henry

Member of the SFI project "Nonlinear Wave-Current

Interactions in the Nearshore".

October 2013 - July 2015 Master degree in Financial Mathematics

Siedlee University of Natural Science and Humanities

Siedlce, Poland

October 2010 - June 2013 Bachelor degree in Financial and Actuarial Mathematics

Siedlee University of Natural Sciences and Humanities

Siedlce, Poland

## Business sector experience

Despite the PhD degree in applied mathematics I show strong interest in financial mathematics and its applications in the business sector. This is supported by my experience gained in the national and international financial banking institution additionally supported by the professional training in the stock market at Siedlee University of Natural Sciences and Humanities.

March 2015 - September 2015 ING BANK ŚLĄSKI, Warsaw, Poland

Auditor in the Internal Audit Department

June 2012 - August 2012 BANK BGZ PNB PARIBAS, Siedlee, Poland

Student placement job

#### Teaching and research experience

During my time in UCC I have successfully completed postgraduate pedagogy module entitled "Teaching and Learning Module for Graduate Studies", supplemented by pedagogy course in Siedlee University of Natural Sciences and Humanities.

October 2015 - now Member of a project "Nonlinear Wave-Current

Interaction in the Nearshore" under the supervision

of dr David Henry supported by Scientific Foundation Ireland

University College Cork

Cork, Ireland

October 2016 - now AM2021 Engineering Mechanics with Transform Methods

Tutor, University College Cork

Cork, Ireland

January 2018 - May 2018 AM3063 Partial Differential Equations with Applications I

Lecturer, University College Cork

Cork, Ireland

January 2016 - May 2016 MA1001 Calculus for Science I & II

Tutor, University College Cork

Cork, Ireland

October 2014 - July 2015 Member of a research team in "Accurate And Approximate

Algorithms For Large-Scale Stochastic Simulation" supported by National Science Centre, Poland

under the supervision of dr Anna Wawrzyńczak-Szaban Siedlce University of Natural Sciences and Humanities

Siedlce, Poland

## Research publications

#### International Research Journals

- 1. M. Kluczek and S. Raphael. Physical properties for Pollard-like surface waves. in preparation
- 2. M. Kluczek. Nonhydrostatic Pollard-like internal geophysical waves. submitted
- 3. M. Kluczek and C.-I. Martin. Dispersion relations for fixed mean-depth flows with two discontinuities in vorticity. *Nonlinear Analysis*, accepted
- 4. M. Kluczek. Physical flow properties for Pollard-like internal water waves. *Journal of Mathematical Physics, accepted*
- 5. M. Kluczek. Exact Pollard-like internal water waves. Journal of Nonlinear Mathematical Physics, accepted
- 6. M. Kluczek. Equatorial water waves with underlying currents in the f-plane approximation. Applicable Analysis, 97:1867–1880, 2018
- 7. A. Rodríguez-Sanjurjo and M. Kluczek. Mean flow properties for equatorially trapped internal water wave—current interactions. *Applicable Analysis*, 96:2333–2345, 2017
- 8. M. Kluczek. Exact and explicit internal equatorial water waves with underlying currents. Journal of Mathematical Fluid Mechanics, 19:305–314, 2017

## Book chapter

1. M. Kluczek and A. Rodríguez-Sanjurjo. Global diffeomorphism of the Lagrangian flow-map for a Pollard-like internal water wave. Birkhäuser, 2018

#### Refereed Conference Proceeding

1. A. Szaban, R. Modzelewska, and M. Kluczek. Numerical methods for solution of the stochastic differential equations equivalent to the non-stationary Parker's transport equation. *Journal of Physics: Conference Series*, 633:1–5, 2015

#### **Invited Seminars**

Applied Mathematics Seminar. University College Cork, Cork, Ireland, 2019.

Applied Mathematics Seminar. University of Plymouth, Plymouth, UK, 2018.

WIT Seminar series in mathematics & physics. Waterford Institute of Technology, Waterford, Ireland, 2017.

## **Invited International Workshops**

Mathematical Aspects of Physical Oceanography. Erwin Schrödinger International Institute for Mathematics and Physics. 26 February-4 March 2018, University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.

Nonlinear Water Waves - an Interdisciplinary Interface. Erwin Schrödinger International Institute for Mathematics and Physics. 3-7 December 2017, University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.

Nonlinear Water Waves. Isaac Newton Institute for Mathematical Sciences. 13-18 August 2017, Cambridge University, Cambridge, UK.

## **Attended Workshops**

Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics (SPH) CPD Course. A two-day continuing professional development course. 10-11 April 2018, University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.